David Perez

Software Engineer

davedevelopmentusa@gmail.com

Summary

Mostly, some of my personal goals include creating applications designed to reduce customer service costs, machine learning, big data and enhanced process management. Consequently, I am constantly concerned with improving my skills in order to exchange knowledge and experiences with others within the field.

Experience

Global Process Competency Owner at ABB's Enterprise Software Product Group

February 2016 - Present (1 year 1 month)

Force.com Developer. Global SFDC Process Competency Owner. DevOps on Salesforce Admin, Configuration, Customization, Deployments and Salesforce.com CRM Solutions.Page Layout, Change Inbound and Outbound Sets, Unit and Test Coverage. Extractions of Salesforce Business Objects to various formats XML, JSON, Data Migration, design of Visual Force Pages, Record Types, Junction Objects, Dashboards and installation of SFO Email Salesforce for Outlook Integration and LFO Lightning For Outlook. Workflows, Approval Processes, Validations Rules, Process Builders, Flows, Custom Reports and Salesforce.com Version Releases Managements Experiences. Technical and Functional Design. Technical Leader Clari Predictive Analytics and Eloqua Marketing Automation. Apex, SOAP, AJAX and Force.com API. Canvas External Applications and Integration Processes. SAP/SFDC Integration. Agile and Waterfall based-technique methodologies. AppExchanges. Milestone PM technical leader and developer. Expertise in Informatica Cloud Management, Version 1, Financial Force PSA, User Management including Permission Sets and Controls, Profiles, Queues, Public Group, Chatter Object, Email Templates and Access Control.

Other Expertise: waffle.io, Slack Collaboration, GitHub, Cloud 9, Heroku, NodeJS, Eclipse Force.com IDE, sublime and SalesforceIDE haoide, Ant Migration Tools and CI tools.

Software Engineer at Apex Data Solutions.LLC

November 2014 - November 2015 (1 year 1 month)

Python, C++ and JS

- Implemented a simple inkStroke tool kit to improve the IO device to electronic veteran records.
- Implemented a DocSet for Vista JS with Dash API Documentation Browser to extract valuable metadata, free code documentation, store snippets and screenshots.
- Redesigned a NoSQL Data Layer and an Object Model called GraphyteDB to provide database system and implemented backwards compatibility for simple storage engine.
- Created the Unit Test Framework with Boost Test Case for NoSOL Database.

• Designed a first software phase of a Web Log Analyzer to record any Web Apache Log Format to track records, security breach or whole and to improve the enterprise business model.

Freelancer at Drupal CMS developer

March 2013 - May 2014 (1 year 3 months)

PHP and HTML

- Designed and created modules to build Car Store Site with dynamic forms and structures. Created and installed specification of the business and principal hosting of the web site.
- Implemented simple web page application with cron of Drupal 8 and Apache Web Server.

Computer Support Specialist at I-Fix-It

August 2013 - February 2014 (7 months)

- Installed and updated network system, routers, AWS and instance of TCP/IP and FTP services.
- Delivered and direct contact of customer services and technical refurbishment.
- Collaborated and contract simple business responsibility and fixed hardware devices and software applications.

Undergraduate at La Universidad de CUJAE

September 2005 - February 2011 (5 years 6 months)

C++ and Java dev

- Implemented a NPL similarity algorithm tool to machine learning with CMap-based methods and open source suite of language analyzers Freeling 2.1.
- Analyzed and designed the Software Architecture and kernel distributions.
- Built app to compute disambiguation mechanism for similes nodes with same taxonomy paths, improved the old platform and developed a text mining module for GRIAL Group.
- Created test case generation tool which creates random XML docs from XML Schema.

Software Developer at AICROS

May 2008 - September 2009 (1 year 5 months)

Design of an API for secure traffic on a specialized network using 256 bit encryption algorithms. Requirements and documentation: analysis and specification. Project planning. Preliminary study of Architecture, Design of UI (desktop). Selection of design patterns and appropriate technologies. Kernel development project. Deployment. Tests. User Manual. Security, data integrity, reliability. Languages and technologies used: C + +, Qt Creator, algorithms based encryption and public key encryption and private API for SHA1, MD5. Microsoft Office.

Projects

Vista JS Docset

June 2015 to Present

Members:David Perez

Web Scrapping script to format and content HTML Vista Documentation.

• Implemented a DocSet for Vista JS with Dash API Documentation Browser to extract valuable metadata, free code documentation, store snippets and screenshots.

InkStroke Tool Kit

March 2015 to Present

Members: David Perez, Stefano Lalli

Implemented an inkStroke app to improve the IO device to electronic veteran records. technologies:

- (SVG, Canvas, Image Processing algorithms and Computer Vision) (2015). Pypotrace and MyScript engine to draw strokes over electronic form, print quick reports and improve EHS (Electronic Health System).
- I was supporting with an excellent contract in describing the layout and principal requirements.

Disambiguation Mechanic and Similarity Algorithmic with CMap (Internship).

September 2009 to Present

Members: David Perez, Alejandro Coutin, Ing. Leandro Sacco, PMP, ITIL, Eriel Estrada

Internship at AI GRIAL Group. ISPJAE. Havana. Cuba.

C++ and Java dev

- Implemented a NPL similarity algorithm tool to machine learning with CMap-based methods and open source suite of language analyzers Freeling 2.1.
- Analyzed and designed the Software Architecture and kernel distributions.
- Built app to compute disambiguation mechanism for similes nodes with same taxonomy paths, improved the old platform and developed a text mining module for GRIAL Group.
- Created test case generation tool which creates random XML docs from XML Schema.

Implementation of encryption algorithms in order to secure data transfer system (Internship). July 2008 to Present

Members: David Perez, Alejandro Coutin, Shouddy Tárano León, Eriel Estrada

Company: AICROS (2008)

Internship as a Software developer in the Applications Development Department at the Software Company for the Construction Minister, AICROS, Havana, Cuba.

Responsibilities: Research and project documentation. Requirements analysis and specification. Project planning. Selection of tools and technologies required. Study of Architecture. Preliminary design of user interfaces (desktop). Design of an API for secure traffic on the network information using 256bit encryption algorithms. Selection of design patterns and appropriate technologies for desktop application development. Kernel development project. Deployment. Tests. Documentation. User Manual. Security, data integrity, reliability.

Technologies and methodologies used: C + +, Qt Creator, algorithms based encryption and public key encryption and private API for SHA1, MD5. Microsoft Office.

Mail's project (Internship).

May 2007 to Present

Members: David Perez, Alejandro Coutin, Eriel Estrada

Developed environment at an important project where our students knew how could use the paradigm of the OOP, and also Computer Programming 2. Otherwise, My team and me had still been building these software and modifying one of the most old interfaces since two months ago while were us being Java Beans. After a while, it was presented in day scientific at CUJAE in more than one occasion.

Multimedia 'Manual de Desastres I y II', enfocado a la educación civil contra desastres naturales, en la CUJAE.

March 2009 to Present

Members: David Perez, Yuliet Espinosa Cruz, Alejandro Coutin

Cliente Final: Departamento de Prevención de Desastres de la Defensa Civil

- Responsabilidades: Búsqueda e investigación previa de documentación necesaria para el proyecto.
 Diseño y creación Biblioteca de Información. Diseño de presentación. Implementación de la multimedia.
 Documentación y Manual de Usuario.
- Tecnologías y metodologías utilizadas: Macromedia Flash 8, Photoshop. Microsoft Office.

CRM Customization

March 2016 to Present

Members: David Perez, Christian R Cordova

Fix issue and work on enhancement release to improve Salesforce.com CRM using Force.com API. Improvement of business process with custom functionality in Opportunity, Support Order, and Project management Milestone PM Open source appExchange.

Salesforce and SAP Integration

November 2016 to Present

Members: David Perez, Christian R Cordova, William Singh, Toni Jacobs

Front and back end system in Salesforce.com integration CRM with SAP system globally. Business adoption and performance engagement process for a new financial and business process. Increase invoice execution and automatic sales order batch flow using Microsoft BizTalk server adapter resource, SAP report batch, IDOC and orchestration process to receive, interpret, parse and send outbound/inbound messages converted to XML schema and csv files using techniques like the inverted conversion and segmentation release version.

Expertise: standard and custom WSDL, SOAPUI, IDOC mapping, Orchestration and Message/Segment release, configuration management.

Self Service Release Notes for Version One

November 2016 to Present

Members: David Perez

The Self-Service release notes is automatic Salesforce web page for Version 1 Integration that should allow for dynamic filtering of data using the allowed Version 1 objects such as Products, Versions, Components and Backlog groups.

CLM Apttus Integration

January 2017 to Present

Members: David Perez, Sunny Chan, Christian R Cordova

Enable new CLM business process adoption in ABB Enterprise Software Group. Installation of new managed packages Apttus Contract, Approval Management, Documentation Generation and DocuSign application. Apttus AWA Migration. Opportunity Screening installation of advanced apttus custom approval management package.

FACE Org Consolidation

February 2017 to Present

Members: David Perez

AWA Opportunity Screening installation and FACE org consolidation.

Skills & Expertise

Software Engineering

Agile Methodologies

JavaScript

HTML

CSS

Python

Databases

NoSQL Engine

Salesforce.com

Force.com

Java

C++

MySQL

HTML5

XML

C#

Data Analysis

Microsoft SQL Server

PostgreSQL

Node.js

JSON

JDOM

Apache Spark

Ruby on Rails

Ruby

UML

Drupal

Eclipse

NetBeans

Visual Studio

Software Development

Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)

Apache Ant

Github

Git

 \mathbf{CI}

Education

Jose Antonio Echeverria Higher Polytechnic Institute

Undergraduate, IT Engineering, 2005 - 2011

Grade: Bachelor's Degree

University of California, Berkeley

Verified Certificates, Computer Science, 2012 - 2013

Massachusetts Institute of Technology

Verified Certificate Introduction to computer Science and Programming Using Python, Python Programming

Language, 2014 - 2015

University of Michigan

Computer Science, 2015

Delft University of Technology

Text Mining and Analytic Course, Tech Mining and Artificial Intelligence, 2015 - 2015

Grade: 2 continuing education units (CEUs) credit course

Courses

Independent Coursework

ISC1002 Caché ObjectScript Basics: Variables and

Operators

IntersystemCache

ISC1001 Caché Objects Introduction

IntersystemCache

LFS101x Introduction to Linux

edx

EAP Fourth Written English Level

HCC

High Intermediate English Level

787578 MDC

EAP Fourth Speaking and Listening English Level

HCC

DemoX edX Demonstration Course edx

Intermediate English Level 748492 MDC

TW3421x Credit Risk Management edx

High Beginning Formerly Basic English Level 731124 MDC

TOEFL Preparation Course FIU: Summer Term 2013

MAS.S69x Big Data and Social Physics edx

Certifications

GT.M Administration and Operations certificate of completion

FIS January 2015

MongoDB for Node.js Developer

MongoDB, Inc. May 2015

edX Verified Certificate for Engineering Software as a Service, Part 1

edX November 2013

edX Verified Certificate for Introduction to Big Data with Apache Spark

edX July 2015

edX Verified Certificate for Learn HTML5 from W3C

edX July 2015

MongoDB for DBAs

MongoDB, Inc. July 2015

edX Verified Certificate for Introduction to Cloud Computing

edX July 2015

edX Verified Certificate for Scalable Machine Learning

edX August 2015

edX Verified Certificate for Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python

edX August 2015

Programming for Everybody (Python)

Coursera Verified Certificates August 2015

edX Professional Certificate for Text Mining & Analytics

edX September 2015

edX Verified Certificate for Engineering Software as a Service, Part 2

edX March 2016

Publications

Multimedia "Manual de Desastres II"

First National Congress on "Health and Disasters" in Cuba March 15, 2009

Authors: David Perez, Alejandro Coutin, Gisele C. Marie, Yuliet Espinosa Cruz

Analysis and description of the use of technology to advance techniques in the medical field.

Honors and Awards

Multimedia "Manual de Desastres I"

Universidad Nacional Agraria de la Habana

October 2008

Languages

Spanish

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

English

(Professional working proficiency)

Organizations

EDX

MOOC Student

July 2013 to Present

It is a non- profit massive open online course (MOOC), aimed at unlimited participation and open access via the web. Our courses are designed to be interesting, fun and rigorous. They are the best courses, from the best professors, and the best schools and span a variety of subjects, from science and technology to the humanities.

Interests

Drupal, Python, Ruby, Oracle Virtualization Databases, edx.org MOOC and other interests.

David Perez

Software Engineer

davedevelopmentusa@gmail.com



6 people have recommended David

"David is a dedicated worker who always seeks to solve customers issues promptly. His can do attitude and ability to work well with others helped the team meet customer expectations. He is an outstanding person who will focus on the details as well as balance various tasks to completion. I highly recommend his work in the Information Technology sector."

— **Christian R Cordova**, *Software Developer*, *ABB's Enterprise Software Product Group*, worked directly with David at ABB's Enterprise Software Product Group

"David it's amazing partner and coworker in the software developing's process and research for new technologies. He is always concerned about the team mates and the persons involved in the work. He is very responsible and interest in guesting the job done as well, in the best fashion possible. He is always looking for new approach. He is a tech enthusiastic and a hard worker person. He is very polite, professional and honest about the job and his teammates."

— Alejandro Coutin, worked directly with David at La Universidad de CUJAE

"David, es una persona con mucha experiencia, detalle y entusiasta. Dentro de mis trabajos con David, he encontrado un profesional analítico esforzado y muy ordenado. Recomiendo totalmente los trabajos expuestos por David."

— Carlos Patricio Arévalo Maulén, worked directly with David at La Universidad de CUJAE

"David es un excelente profesional y que se destacó en todas las laboras que realizó en la Universidad. Un gran compañero siempre bien de dispuesto a ayudar y colaborar con sus colegas, posee fuerte espíritu de equipo y capacidad de resolver problemas."

— **Leandro Ulises Sacco**, worked directly with David at La Universidad de CUJAE

"David is a hard working person who likes to get all his tasks done as soon as possible. He is respectful, cooperative, proactive, and responsible person. All the time he tries to be a valuable person for the services of the team. He is often looking for new challenges to solve in real contexts applying new technologies, and he likes a lot basically work in team environments to collaborate and help as much as he can."

— Oscar	Gonzalez,	studied	with	David a	t Jose	Antonio	Echeverria	Higher	Polyte	echnic	Institute
---------	-----------	---------	------	---------	--------	---------	------------	--------	--------	--------	-----------

"Es un persona muy profesional, con la cual puedes contar en calquer momento. Exelente persona."

— **Mario Javier Lombao Martínez**, studied with David at Jose Antonio Echeverria Higher Polytechnic Institute

Contact David on LinkedIn